{
    "id": "208de2e063174fa88269dac153d5dc60",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He was loved and respected by the people ...................................",
            "description": "Prepositions can come either before relative pronouns or at the end of relative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "that he worked with",
                "Either could be used here",
                "with whom he worked"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the house .............................. I was born.",
            "description": "In relative clauses 'where' can be used instead of 'in which'.",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "in which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "In that year she met James, ....................... she was later to marry.",
            "description": "Whom is the correct option here, but who is also possible in an informal style.",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "who",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Is this all ........................... is left?",
            "description": "After quantifiers like all, every, some and any, we prefer 'that' to 'which'.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is the best film ................................ has ever been made about dementia.",
            "description": "After superlatives, we prefer 'that' to 'which'.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "All ............................. you say is true.",
            "description": "What cannot be used instead of that.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I saw a girl .................................. beauty took my breath away.",
            "description": "Whose is a relative possessive word used before nouns in the same way as his, her, its or their.",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "which",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He has launched a business .....................………. I have forgotten.",
            "description": "Instead of whose, we can use of which",
            "answers": [
                "whose name",
                "the name of which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "..................... she said made me angry.",
            "description": "What means the things which.",
            "answers": [
                "What",
                "That",
                "Which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The only thing ……………….. keeps me awake is coffee.",
            "description": "'What' can only be used to mean ‘the things which’.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We have …………………. we need.",
            "description": "That which is possible here but it is unusual in modern English.",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He got married again a few months later, ..................... .. surprised everybody.",
            "description": "Which can refer to the whole of a relative clause.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}